(703) 300-4392 jmeyer41@gmail.com <u>www.joeymeyer.com</u> <u>github.com/joeymeyer</u>

Profile

Experienced software engineer with extensive background building **iOS** apps. Recently drawn to **computer vision**, **machine learning**, and **robotics** through my latest project—a chess playing robot. Motivated to use my thorough understanding of iOS while incorporating these interests.

Experience

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, RASPBERRY TURK PROJECT – 2016

Built a fully functioning robot that can play chess. Developed deep convolutional neural network to recognize chess pieces using TensorFlow. Robotic arm consisting of multiple servos and an electromagnet for picking up pieces controlled by Python running on Raspberry Pi.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, LIVINGSOCIAL – 2011-2015

Built and maintained the LivingSocial consumer iOS app

- App had millions of users and millions of dollars in transactions (top Lifestyle app)
- Built significant features, and was a core maintainer of the code base
- Created and maintained web APIs for the app
- Built features that were featured by Apple in the App Store
- Communicated across many internal teams to accomplish coordinated goals
- Taught iOS bootcamp to internal engineers from different teams

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, OMNIS, INC. – 2011

Built prototype iOS app and a complete Django backend during my summer at Omnis

IOS DEVELOPER, 101 GRADS – 2010-2011

Built an iOS app to help keep track of completed goals associated with the book, 101 Things to Do Before You Graduate by Julien Gordon

TECHNICAL INTERN, MITRE – 2009-2011

Trained a neural network for estimating complex computations in an agent based model among other projects; coauthored a publication in The Journal of Defense Modeling and Simulation: Applications, Methodology, Technology

Education

George Mason University – BS Computer Science 2012 – Cum Laude 3.64 GPA – Dean's List Fall 2008 to Fall 2011

Skills

Objective-C, Swift, Git, Ruby on Rails, Python